<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reinforcement Learning on The Journeyman Modeler</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/categories/reinforcement-learning/</link><description>Recent content in Reinforcement Learning on The Journeyman Modeler</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 18:59:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jmodeler.github.io/categories/reinforcement-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Resolving Errors when Creating Your First MineRL Agent</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-errors-when-creating-your-first-minerl-agent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-errors-when-creating-your-first-minerl-agent/</guid><description>In this post, I lay out the steps to follow to resolve the errors you see when creating your first MineRL agent on a macOS. This is a continuation of this post, which looks at resolving install errors on the minerl package.
I borrow heavily from this github issue comment.
Clone the repository using the terminal command below
git clone https://github.com/minerllabs/minerl.git This will create a minerl directory. Make sure that the path to the cloned repository does not have spaces in it (i.</description></item><item><title>Resolving Install Errors with MineRL</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-install-errors-with-minerl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-install-errors-with-minerl/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll resolve an error that one might face when trying to install the minerl Python package. The instructions to install this package can be found here.
Using the instructions above, when I used the install command (pip3 install git+https://github.com/minerllabs/minerl), I got the following error (only the relevant part is shown here): Note: Some input files use or override a deprecated API. Note: Recompile with -Xlint:deprecation for details. Note: Some input files use unchecked or unsafe operations.</description></item></channel></rss>