<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on The Journeyman Modeler</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on The Journeyman Modeler</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jmodeler.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Resolving Install Errors with NVlabs imaginaire</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-install-errors-with-nvlabs-imaginaire/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-install-errors-with-nvlabs-imaginaire/</guid><description>TL;DR: I need to install the NVlabs imaginaire package for a project (more details in a later post). I walk through the installation steps and how to resolve any errors you might encounter.
I need to install the NVlabs imaginaire package, I follow the instructions here.
As explained in a previous post, I use pyenv to handle various versions of python and I&amp;rsquo;m currently using version 3.10.5:
$ pyenv versions system * 3.</description></item><item><title>Resolving Errors when Creating Your First MineRL Agent</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-errors-when-creating-your-first-minerl-agent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-errors-when-creating-your-first-minerl-agent/</guid><description>In this post, I lay out the steps to follow to resolve the errors you see when creating your first MineRL agent on a macOS. This is a continuation of this post, which looks at resolving install errors on the minerl package.
I borrow heavily from this github issue comment.
Clone the repository using the terminal command below
git clone https://github.com/minerllabs/minerl.git This will create a minerl directory. Make sure that the path to the cloned repository does not have spaces in it (i.</description></item><item><title>Resolving Install Errors with MineRL</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-install-errors-with-minerl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/resolving-install-errors-with-minerl/</guid><description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll resolve an error that one might face when trying to install the minerl Python package. The instructions to install this package can be found here.
Using the instructions above, when I used the install command (pip3 install git+https://github.com/minerllabs/minerl), I got the following error (only the relevant part is shown here): Note: Some input files use or override a deprecated API. Note: Recompile with -Xlint:deprecation for details. Note: Some input files use unchecked or unsafe operations.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Python to Run on Rmarkdown</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/setting-up-python-to-run-on-rmarkdown/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/setting-up-python-to-run-on-rmarkdown/</guid><description>I use the Hugo academic template along with Rstudio’s Blogdown package to generate and deploy this website to github pages. I use this setup to generate blog posts (via Rmarkdown) that render \(\LaTeX\) math and output from R code.
Sometimes, I’d like to run Python code inside Rmarkdown too, and this is supported, via the reticulate package. That said, the following steps need to be followed to make sure everything runs smoothly (all of these steps worked on a macOS Ventura operating system)</description></item></channel></rss>