<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scientific Computing on The Journeyman Modeler</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/categories/scientific-computing/</link><description>Recent content in Scientific Computing on The Journeyman Modeler</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 07:55:39 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jmodeler.github.io/categories/scientific-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Numerical Integration with Sparse Grids</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/numerical-integration-with-sparse-grids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/numerical-integration-with-sparse-grids/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently read a paper (&lt;a href="#ref-heiss2008likelihood" &gt;Heiss and Winschel 2008&lt;/a&gt;) that advocated the use of certain techniques (Sparse Grids, SG henceforth) in numerical integration to calculate likelihood functions, as opposed to using Monte Carlo (MC henceforth) methods for the same. While approximating integrals with MC methods are simpler to implement, they might lead to integral values with considerable simulation error (&lt;a href="#ref-skrainka2011high" &gt;Skrainka and Judd 2011&lt;/a&gt;). This post attempts to demonstrate the claim in Skrainka and Judd (&lt;a href="#ref-skrainka2011high" &gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;) using two very simple integrals, to which we already know the value. I attempt to compare the outcomes from using MC and SG.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Homotopy Principle: Simple Examples</title><link>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/the-homotopy-principle-simple-examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jmodeler.github.io/posts/the-homotopy-principle-simple-examples/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This post presents 2 simple examples of the homotopy principle applied to (fairly easy) linear and nonlinear systems of equations. At a very abstract level, given a system of equations for which a solution is needed, we convert this system to one whose solution we already know (or is easy to find out), and then bend this system till we get the solution to the original set of equations. These methods have very broad applications (&lt;a href="#ref-garciapathways" &gt;Garcia and Zangwill 1981&lt;/a&gt;), and have been applied in the context of finding equlibria in Static Games (&lt;a href="#ref-Bajari2010" &gt;Bajari et al. 2010&lt;/a&gt;) and Dynamic Games (&lt;a href="#ref-Borkovsky2010" &gt;Borkovsky, Doraszelski, and Kryukov 2010&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>