<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity | The Journeyman Modeler</title><link>https://jmodeler.github.io/category/productivity/</link><atom:link href="https://jmodeler.github.io/category/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Productivity</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://jmodeler.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Productivity</title><link>https://jmodeler.github.io/category/productivity/</link></image><item><title>Setting up Python to Run on Rmarkdown</title><link>https://jmodeler.github.io/post/setting-up-python-to-run-on-rmarkdown/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jmodeler.github.io/post/setting-up-python-to-run-on-rmarkdown/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I use the &lt;a href="https://github.com/wowchemy/starter-hugo-academic">Hugo academic template&lt;/a> along with Rstudio’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/rstudio/blogdown">Blogdown&lt;/a> package to generate and deploy this website to &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">github pages&lt;/a>. I use this setup to generate blog posts (via &lt;a href="https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/">Rmarkdown&lt;/a>) that render &lt;span class="math inline">\(\LaTeX\)&lt;/span> math and output from R code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes, I’d like to run Python code inside Rmarkdown too, and this is &lt;a href="https://bookdown.org/yihui/rmarkdown-cookbook/eng-python.html">supported&lt;/a>, via the &lt;a href="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/reticulate/index.html">reticulate&lt;/a> package. That said, the following steps need to be followed to make sure everything runs smoothly (all of these steps worked on a macOS Ventura operating system)&lt;/p>
&lt;ol style="list-style-type: decimal">
&lt;li>In your Rmarkdown file, always have this code chunk to setup Python use for later:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre class="r">&lt;code># setup for using python code later in the page
# import the reticulate package
library(reticulate)
# specify the version of python to use
use_python(&amp;quot;/Users/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/.pyenv/shims/python&amp;quot;)&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ol start="2" style="list-style-type: decimal">
&lt;li>&lt;p>Note: In the chunk above, replace &lt;code>&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code> with your username. In addition, I use &lt;code>pyenv&lt;/code> to manage python versions on my system, as &lt;a href="https://blog.teclado.com/how-to-use-pyenv-manage-python-versions/">explained here&lt;/a>. If you don’t have &lt;code>pyenv&lt;/code> already, be sure to set it up using the instructions in the previous link.&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;p>You might hit an error when you run a python code chunk in Rmarkdown:&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Error: &amp;#39;/Users/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/.pyenv/shims/python&amp;#39; was not built with a shared library.
reticulate can only bind to copies of Python built with &amp;#39;--enable-shared&amp;#39;.
Execution halted
Error : Failed to render content/post/&amp;lt;name_of_post&amp;gt;/index.en.Rmd&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ol start="4" style="list-style-type: decimal">
&lt;li>&lt;p>This just means I must build a version of python with the &lt;code>--enable-shared&lt;/code> flag. I do this using &lt;code>pyenv&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;p>First, choose a version of python that you want to use. You can do this by going to the terminal and typing&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> pyenv install --list&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ol start="6" style="list-style-type: decimal">
&lt;li>This should show you a long output, some of them will be python versions, as shown below:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> ...
3.10.1
3.10.2
3.10.3
3.10.4
3.10.5
3.10.6
3.10.7
3.10.8
3.10.9
3.10.10
3.11.0
...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ol start="7" style="list-style-type: decimal">
&lt;li>Choose an appropriate version and use the command below to install said version, like so (in the example below, I choose to install 3.11.0):&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> env PYTHON_CONFIGURE_OPTS=&amp;quot;--enable-shared&amp;quot; pyenv install 3.11.0&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ol start="8" style="list-style-type: decimal">
&lt;li>In the previous step, note the &lt;code>--enable-shared&lt;/code> option has now been added&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We now want to set this Python version to be the global Python version. Type the following command (replace 3.11.0 in the command below with the version you installed):&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> pyenv global 3.11.0&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ol start="10" style="list-style-type: decimal">
&lt;li>You can also check if the global version set is the correct version using the following command:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> pyenv versions&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;ol start="10" style="list-style-type: decimal">
&lt;li>&lt;p>If you’re using python packages (i.e. &lt;code>numpy&lt;/code>, &lt;code>pandas&lt;/code>, etc.) in your code chunks, make sure to install them first (i.e. by using &lt;code>pip3 install numpy&lt;/code>, &lt;code>pip3 install pandas&lt;/code>, etc. in the terminal)&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;p>With all of this set up, you should no longer see the error above when you knit Rmarkdown documents with Python code chunks in them.&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Completing Projects at Work</title><link>https://jmodeler.github.io/post/completing-projects-at-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jmodeler.github.io/post/completing-projects-at-work/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This is a post inspired by a conversation I had with a colleague, Ryan. Over a very short period, he had completed an impressive portfolio of work projects, and always had something better in the pipeline. I asked him what he did when starting on anything, and he very kindly shared his method to get (most) things done at work (and in life, where applicable). In the following post, anything marked in &lt;span style="color: Tomato;"> tomato-red &lt;/span> is input from him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan’s method to do anything in life (abstract version):&lt;/p>
&lt;ol style="list-style-type: decimal">
&lt;li>&lt;p>Determine what is being asked of you (or what you want to achieve). What problem are you trying to solve? Do not fall victim to the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XY_problem">XY problem&lt;/a>, be very clear about the deliverable expected. Check and re-check (or re-assess, in case this is a personal goal) with your boss/business partner/end goal &lt;span style="color: Tomato;">regularly&lt;/span>.&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;p>With a clear deliverable in mind, now clearly formulate the steps to be taken to get closer to said deliverable&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;p>Now, do you have all the skills/knowledge to do the steps yourself? Great! Make a plan to work on each step and stick to it. &lt;span style="color: Tomato;">Try to make a plan on how much work will be required time wise to progress through each step. This will also help you learn how good (or bad) you are at estimating time/specific tasks.&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color: Tomato;"> I highly recommend reading &lt;a href="https://archive.fo/kHhdM">this blog post&lt;/a> about what to tackle first. He recommends basically making the smallest version of what you need that includes all the component parts. This helps you discover compatibility/integration issues up front that can wreck a project if they’re discovered late.&lt;br />
&lt;/span>&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;p>If you see there are gaps in your knowledge, you have two options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Learn everything you need to know to plug the knowledge gap (&lt;span style="color: Tomato;">generally terrifying and not recommended&lt;/span>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find someone else who had the same problem and try to replicate what they’ve done. Google is your friend! (&lt;span style="color: Tomato;">generally where I start, using a &lt;a href="https://archive.fo/x5C54">tracer bullet&lt;/a>&lt;/span>). Once you’ve found a solution, follow the process outlined in step 3. and make progress on your work.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;p>As you keep working on your steps, DOCUMENT EVERYTHING. This will help you do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you need to (or want to) move on to another project, you can hand this over to someone else and easily create a succession plan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If this project is a personal goal, you have a record of what you did. This will serve as a reference when you need to redo something like this in the future.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;span style="color: Tomato;">If your memory is anything like mine, it’s not great and you work on a lot. Your own documentation will help you know why you did something&lt;/span>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;span style="color: Tomato;">It helps guide others through how to learn a topic&lt;/span>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;span style="color: Tomato;">It can serve as a record of what work was done which can be useful as an archive, or for ideas for other work. Was one process a nightmare that you spent half your time on? Maybe that should be tackled next&lt;/span>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>